The Jumbo Yearbook UP024
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
The Jumbo Yearbook
1916 -- 2020
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office for Campus Life
Jumbo (Yearbook)
UP024
1.45 Linear Feet
101 Volumes
104 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Biographical / Historical
The Jumbo is the yearbook of the undergraduate colleges of Tufts University. It has been published annually since 1916, though the the title "The Jumbo" was first used for the 1917 edition. Over the years it has been known alternately as the Jumbo Book or simply Jumbo. In later years the yearbooks are often untitled.
Custodial History
The yearbook of Tufts University, undergraduate arts and sciences. The Jumbo replaced the Brown and Blue, which ceased publication in 1904. The first Jumbo Book was published in 1917, though a 1916 yearbook titled simply, "Tufts 1916" also exists. Other books were published in 1922, 1925, and 1928. The Jumbo has been continuously published since 1928. This collection also contains one issue of Taps from 1920 and Elephas from 1921, which functioned as a yearbook.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains copies of the annual Jumbo beginning in 1917, as well as a Tufts yearbook from 1916 (not officially titled "The Jumbo," but in the same tradition.) The Jumbo appeared only sporadically at first, in 1922, 1925, and 1928, and thereafter appeared annually. Starting in 2012 it was published as the Senior Memory Book.
- The Jumbo, 1917 -- 2020; UP024.001; 0.25 Linear Feet; 101 Volumes; 104 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  The yearbook of Tufts University, undergraduate arts and sciences. The Jumbo replaced the Brown and Blue, which ceased publication in 1904. The first Jumbo Book was published in 1917. Other books were published in 1922, 1925, and 1928. The Jumbo has been continuously published since 1928.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - The Jumbo, 1917; UP024.001.001.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 24 Megabytes (Box Volume 1)
    - Madeline Bernard, Jackson, 1917; UP024.001.001.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 1)
      Four female students, including Madeline Bernard, bottom left
      People; Students; Women; Jackson College; Black people; Madeline Bernard; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1922; UP024.001.002.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 19 Megabytes (Box Volume 2)
  - The Jumbo, 1925; UP024.001.003.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 23 Megabytes (Box Volume 3)
  - The Jumbo, 1927; UP024.001.004.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 10 Megabytes (Box Volume 4)
    - Mae Tyson Wright, 1927; UP024.001.004.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 4)
      Caption: Mae Tyson Wright, A.B. in History, Baltimore, Maryland, "The secret of success is constancy to purpose", Cushing Academy. Class Basketball (1), (2); Class Tennis (2); History Club (3), (4).
      People; Students; Women; Black people; Wright, Mae Tyson; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1928; UP024.001.005.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box Volume 5)
  - The Jumbo, 1929; UP024.001.006.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box Volume 6)
  - The Jumbo, 1930; UP024.001.007.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box Volume 7)
  - The Jumbo, 1931; UP024.001.008.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 23 Megabytes (Box Volume 8)
  - The Jumbo, 1932; UP024.001.009.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 19 Megabytes (Box Volume 9)
  - The Jumbo, 1933; UP024.001.010.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 17 Megabytes (Box Volume 10)
    - The Letter Men, 1933; UP024.001.010.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 10)
      Herman Tyrance (back row, third from right)
      People; Football; Student activities; Black people; Tyrance, Herman; Tufts University
    - Grinnell Punting Out against Massachusetts State, 1933; UP024.001.010.00001.00002 (Box Volume 10)
      William Grinnell punting the ball in a game against Massachusetts State, page 131.
      People; Football; Sports; People; Grinnell, William G. 'Johnny'
  - The Jumbo, 1934; UP024.001.011.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 13 Megabytes (Box Volume 11)
  - The Jumbo, 1935; UP024.001.012.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 13 Megabytes (Box Volume 12)
    - Tufts Football Team, 1935; UP024.001.012.00001.00001 (Box Volume 12)
      Group photograph of the Tufts football team, page 120.
      People; Football; Sports; Grinnell, William G. 'Johnny'
  - The Jumbo, 1936; UP024.001.013.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 14 Megabytes (Box Volume 13)
  - The Jumbo, 1937; UP024.001.014.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 14 Megabytes (Box Volume 14)
    - Women's Basketball Team, 1937; UP024.001.014.00001.00001; Unknown (Box data_value_missing_e4a58656891e63a1db40015285a89ec6)
      Irma Thompson, captain, center
      People; Basketball (Women's); Students; Women; Black people; Irma Thompson; Tufts University
    - Women's Field Hockey, 1937; UP024.001.014.00001.00002; Unknown (Box Volume 14)
      Irma Thompson (second row, far right)
      People; Field Hockey; Student activities; Thompson, Irma; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1938; UP024.001.015.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 15 Megabytes (Box data_value_missing_e4a58656891e63a1db40015285a89ec6)
  - The Jumbo, 1939; UP024.001.016.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 17 Megabytes (Box Volume 16)
  - The Jumbo, 1940; UP024.001.017.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 15 Megabytes (Box Volume 17)
  - The Jumbo, 1941; UP024.001.018.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 14 Megabytes (Box Volume 18)
  - The Jumbo, 1942; UP024.001.019.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 18 Megabytes (Box Volume 19)
  - The Jumbo, 1943; UP024.001.020.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 18 Megabytes (Box Volume 20)
  - The Jumbo, 1946; UP024.001.022.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 2 Megabytes (Box Volume 22)
  - The Jumbo, 1947; UP024.001.023.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 22 Megabytes (Box Volume 23)
  - The Jumbo, 1948; UP024.001.024.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 19 Megabytes (Box Volume 24)
  - The Jumbo, 1949; UP024.001.025.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 30 Megabytes (Box Volume 25)
  - The Jumbo, 1950; UP024.001.026.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 31 Megabytes (Box Volume 26)
  - The Jumbo, 1951; UP024.001.027.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 27 Megabytes (Box Volume 27)
    - Jackson Class Officers, 1951; UP024.001.027.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 27)
      Front Row: J. Littlefield (Sec.), I. Dugger (V.Pres.), Second Row: M. Fear (Marshal), A. Holland (Historian), L. Gavrelis (Pres.), A. Kelley (Treas.)
      People; Clubs; Student activities; Students; Dugger, Ione; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1952; UP024.001.028.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 46 Megabytes (Box Volume 28)
  - The Jumbo, 1953; UP024.001.029.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 36 Megabytes (Box Volume 29)
  - The Jumbo, 1954; UP024.001.030.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 33 Megabytes (Box Volume 30)
  - The Jumbo, 1955; UP024.001.031.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 32 Megabytes (Box Volume 31)
  - The Jumbo, 1956; UP024.001.032.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 33 Megabytes (Box Volume 32)
  - The Jumbo, 1957; UP024.001.033.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 29 Megabytes (Box Volume 33)
  - The Jumbo, 1958; UP024.001.034.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 30 Megabytes (Box Volume 34)
  - The Jumbo, 1959; UP024.001.035.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 28 Megabytes (Box Volume 35)
    - Forensic Council, 1959; UP024.001.035.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 35)
      Forensic Council Seated: W. Schneider, Sec.; Inez Smith, Pres.; A. Bornstein, Vice-Pres.; M. Loeb. Standing: W. Starr; J. Lewis, Adv.; S. Rostand, Treas.
      People; Clubs; Student activities; Students; Black people; Smith, Inez; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1960; UP024.001.036.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 38 Megabytes (Box Volume 36)
  - The Jumbo, 1961; UP024.001.037.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 44 Megabytes (Box Volume 37)
    - Women's Volleyball, 1961; UP024.001.037.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 37)
      Lorene Douglas (first row, fourth from left)
      People; Student activities; Basketball (Women's); Douglas, Lorene; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1962; UP024.001.038.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 31 Megabytes (Box Volume 38)
    - Officers: Class of 1963, 1962; UP024.001.038.00001.00001 (Box Volume 38)
      Student activities; Black people; image/tiff; Poole, Thomas; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1963; UP024.001.039.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 31 Megabytes (Box Volume 39)
    - Men's Soccer, 1963; UP024.001.039.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 39)
      Thomas Poole (first row, fourth from left), S. Babigide (second row, 6th from right)
      Soccer; Athletics; Black people; Babigide, S.; Poole, Thomas; Tufts University
    - Lorene M. Douglas, 1963; UP024.001.039.00001.00002 (Box Volume 39)
      Students; Black people; Women; Douglas, Lorene; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1964; UP024.001.040.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 27 Megabytes (Box Volume 40)
  - The Jumbo, 1965; UP024.001.041.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 35 Megabytes (Box Volume 41)
  - The Jumbo, 1966; UP024.001.042.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 26 Megabytes (Box Volume 42)
  - The Jumbo, 1967; UP024.001.043.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 35 Megabytes (Box Volume 43)
  - The Jumbo, 1968; UP024.001.044.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 43 Megabytes (Box Volume 44)
  - The Jumbo, 1969; UP024.001.045.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 26 Megabytes (Box Volume 45)
    - Charles Nathaniel Jordan, 1969; UP024.001.045.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 45)
      Yearbook entry for Charles Jordan
      People; Students; Black people; Jordan, Charles; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1970; UP024.001.046.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 14 Megabytes (Box Volume 46)
    - William B. Richardson, 1970; UP024.001.046.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 46)
      Yearbook photo for Bill Richardson, p. 106.
      People; Students; Richardson, Bill, 1947 Nov. 15-
  - The Jumbo, 1970; UP024.001.047.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 29 Megabytes (Box Volume 47)
  - The Jumbo, 1971; UP024.001.048.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 24 Megabytes (Box Volume 48)
  - The Jumbo, 1972; UP024.001.049.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 35 Megabytes (Box Volume 49)
  - The Jumbo, 1973; UP024.001.050.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box Volume 50)
  - The Jumbo, 1974; UP024.001.051.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 33 Megabytes (Box Volume 51)
  - The Jumbo, 1971 -- 1975; UP024.001.052.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 30 Megabytes (Box Volume 52)
  - The Jumbo, 1976; UP024.001.053.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 35 Megabytes (Box Volume 53)
  - The Jumbo, 1977; UP024.001.054.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 41 Megabytes (Box Volume 54)
  - The Jumbo, 1978; UP024.001.055.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 43 Megabytes (Box Volume 55)
  - The Jumbo, 1979; UP024.001.056.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 29 Megabytes (Box Volume 56)
  - The Jumbo, 1980; UP024.001.057.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 30 Megabytes (Box Volume 57)
    - The Jumbo, page 196, photo 1, 1980; UP024.001.057.00001.00001 (Box Volume 57)
      Football pictures from the Jumbo, 1980.
  - The Jumbo, 1981; UP024.001.058.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 30 Megabytes (Box Volume 58)
    - African American Dance Troupe / UHURU, 1981; UP024.001.058.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 58)
      Caption: The Tufts African American Dance Troupe, UHURU, was founded by the former director of the African-American center, Patricia Collins, in 1977...
      People; Clubs; Student activities; Black people; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1982; UP024.001.059.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 27 Megabytes (Box Volume 59)
    - Afro American Society, 1982; UP024.001.059.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 59)
      People; Clubs; Student activities; Black people; Students; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1983; UP024.001.060.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 69 Megabytes (Box Volume 60)
  - The Jumbo, 1984; UP024.001.061.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 46 Megabytes (Box Volume 61)
    - Third Day Vocal Ensemble, 1959; UP024.001.061.00001.00001; Unknown (Box Volume 61)
      Caption: The Third Day Vocal Ensemble was founded 3 years ago by black students who felt a need for a choir to sing and share with the campus different types of Black American Music. Each year, Third Day participates in Kwanza, sings at neighborhood churches and participates in Protestant services as Goddard Chapel
      People; Clubs; Students; Black people; Student activities; Tufts University
  - The Jumbo, 1985; UP024.001.062.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 50 Megabytes (Box Volume 62)
  - The Jumbo, 1986; UP024.001.063.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 45 Megabytes (Box Volume 63)
  - The Jumbo, 1987; UP024.001.064.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 47 Megabytes (Box Volume 64)
  - The Jumbo, 1988; UP024.001.065.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 37 Megabytes (Box Volume 65)
  - The Jumbo, 1989; UP024.001.066.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 41 Megabytes (Box Volume 66)
  - The Jumbo, 1990; UP024.001.067.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 40 Megabytes (Box Volume 67)
  - The Jumbo, 1991; UP024.001.068.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 40 Megabytes (Box Volume 68)
  - The Jumbo, 1992; UP024.001.069.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 42 Megabytes (Box Volume 69)
  - The Jumbo, 1993; UP024.001.070.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 34 Megabytes (Box Volume 70)
  - The Jumbo, 1994; UP024.001.071.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 31 Megabytes (Box Volume 71)
  - The Jumbo, 1995; UP024.001.072.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 41 Megabytes (Box Volume 72)
  - The Jumbo, 1996; UP024.001.073.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 33 Megabytes (Box Volume 73)
  - The Jumbo, 1997; UP024.001.074.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 52 Megabytes (Box Volume 74)
  - The Jumbo, 2000; UP024.001.075.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 44 Megabytes (Box Volume 75)
  - The Jumbo, 2001; UP024.001.076.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 47 Megabytes (Box Volume 76)
  - The Jumbo, 1998; UP024.001.077.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 44 Megabytes (Box Volume 77)
  - The Jumbo, 1999; UP024.001.078.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 45 Megabytes (Box Volume 78)
  - The Jumbo, 2002; UP024.001.079.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 38 Megabytes (Box Volume 79)
  - The Jumbo, 2003; UP024.001.080.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 46 Megabytes (Box Volume 80)
  - The Jumbo, 2004; UP024.001.081.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 34 Megabytes (Box Volume 81)
  - The Jumbo, 2020; UP024.000121 (Volume 100, Volume 101)
    Senior memory book.
  - The Jumbo, 2005; UP024.001.082.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 31 Megabytes (Box Volume 82)
  - The Jumbo, 2006; UP024.001.083.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 35 Megabytes (Box Volume 83)
  - The Jumbo, 2007; UP024.001.084.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 28 Megabytes (Box Volume 84)
  - The Jumbo, 2008; UP024.001.085.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 25 Megabytes (Box Volume 85)
  - The Jumbo, 2009; UP024.001.086.001; 1 Digital Object(s); 32 Megabytes (Box Volume 86)
  - Taps, 1920; UP024.001.087.00001 (Box Volume 87)
    No Reading Room copy. Class book published in 1920 by the class of 1921. First book of undergraduate activities attempted since 1917.
  - Elephas, 1921; UP024.001.088.00001 (Box Shared 138)
    Class book published in 1921 by the class of 1922.
  - The Jumbo, 2010; UP024.001.089.001 (Box Volume 89)
  - The Jumbo, 2011; UP024.001.090.00001 (Box Volume 90)
  - The Jumbo, 2012; UP024.001.092.00001 (Box Volume 92)
    Senior Memory Book.
  - The Jumbo, 2013; UP024.001.093.00001 (Box Volume 93)
    Additional copy in reading room. Senior Memory Book.
  - The Jumbo, 2014; UP024.001.094.00001 (Box Volume 94)
  - The Jumbo, 2015; UP024.001.095.00001 (Box Volume 95)
  - The Jumbo, 2016; UP024.001.096.00001 (Volume 96)
  - The Jumbo, 2017; UP024.001.097.00001 (Volume 97)
  - The Jumbo, 2018; UP024.001.098.00001 (Volume 98)
  - The Jumbo, 2019; UP024.001.099.00001 (Volume 99)
- The Jumbo, 1916; UP024.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains the first yearbook to be released at Tufts after Brown and Blue ceased publication in 1904. It is not officially called "The Jumbo," but it represents an attempt "to furnish a graduating class with a memento of the Hill in word and picture." This yearbook was moved from the MacJannet collection (see note in MS024.001.142.00007).
  This series contains one item.
  - The Jumbo, 1916; UP024.002.091.00001 (Box Shared 139)
    No Reading Room copy. This publication does not officially hold "The Jumbo" title. The front plate of this yearbook reads: "This is the first attempt since 1904 to furnish a graduating class with a memento of the 'Hill' in word and picture. Bearing in mind the results of former and more elaborate ventures of this nature, we have aimed to eliminate all but the most interesting material." This yearbook was originally removed from the MacJannet collection (see note in MS024.001.142.00007).